<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Human-Onepiece</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/ItlMSW6ztZTm">u/Mr-Silvers and Eiichiro Oda</author>
		<update version="3.11.1">
			<file name="race-human-onepiece.xml" url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/ItlMSW6ztZTm"/>
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Human-Onepiece" type="Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACE_HUMAN">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">By far the most numerous of all races are the humans.Inhabiting the entire world from the a hundred and seventy kingdoms to the halls of Marie Geoise upon the Red Line, the humans have spread all across the four seas. Few humans are defined by their race, however. A varied kind from every echelon of society, one would find it difficult to place a blanket terms on humans as a whole. They can be fearless heroes, intrepid adventurers, craven villains despicable tyrants, pirates seeking freedom or marine soldiers seeking order. The only surefire way to know where a human's heart lies is to look at the flag she flies, which can be as manifold as the stars upon the night sky.</p>
			
			<h4>RESTLESS HEARTS</h4>
			<p>Among all the races, humans are the most likely to set off on the sea in search of adventure, riches, purpose or power. Even considering their vast majority in the world, there is still something within their hearts that calls them to the sea. Because of this, many different tribes of humans have appeared all over the world, each with their own distinct culture and quirks. Each single island is more like a country in its own right with customs and history unique to the people living there since centuries back.</p>
				
			<h4>HISTORY OF CONFLICT</h4>
			<p>Among the one hundred and seventy kingdoms that make up the world government, all but one is a human kingdom giving the human race an indiscriminate claim to being the dominant race in the world. Adding to that, they are also the most technologically advanced and organized race, giving them a massive geopolitical edge in the state of the world. However, human history is one of strife and conflict, both amongst themselves and against other races. Their society is heavily fractured by deep-seated socioeconomical inequalities; the world nobles can make any demands with the world government's full support, while countries who cannot pay the taxes are left at the mercy of pirates and marauders. While life on the sea is a harsh one, it is at the very least an equal existence for all who travel upon it.</p>

			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>One ability score of your choice increases by 2, and another one increases by 1. Alternatively,three ability scores of your choice increase by 1.<br />
				<span class="feature">Age.</span>Humans reach adulthood in their late teens and live less than a century.<br />
				<!-- (removed in Errata v3.0) -->
				<!-- <span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Humans tend toward no particular alignment. The best and the worst are found among them.<br /> -->
				<span class="feature">Size.</span>Humans vary greatly in size, standing anywhere between 3 to well over 10 feet, with those belonging to the long-leg tribe reaching heights above 15 feet. Your size is your choice of small or medium.<br />
				<span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.<br />
				<span class="feature">Languages.</span>You can speak, read, and write Common and one extra language of your choice. Humans typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with, including obscure dialects.<br />
				<span class="feature">Human Determination</span>Once when you're reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can choose to fall to 1 hit point instead. You must finish a long rest before you can use this trait again.<br />
				<span class="feature">Subrace.</span>Choose between standard human, kuja, long-arm, long-leg, snakeneck or three-eye tribe.<br />
			</p>        
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Ander, Blath, Bran, Frath, Geth, Lander, Luth, Malcer, Stor, Taman, Urth, Zoro</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Amafrey, Betha, Cefrey, Kethra, Mara, Olga, Robin, Silifrey, Westra</set>
			<set name="names" type="surname">Brightwood, Helder, Hornraven, Lackman, Law, Monkey, Nico, Ronoroa, Stormwind, Windrivver</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}} {{surname}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d12">4'9"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d4">110 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Improvement Type" source="Internal" supports="Custom Ability Score Improvement Option"/>			
			<stat  name= "innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>			
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<select type="Language" name="Customized Language" supports="Custom Race Language"  />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" name="Human Determination" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_HUMAN_DETERMINATION"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" name="Human Subrace" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_SUBRACE" /> 
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Medium" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_SIZE">
		<supports>Human-Onepiece-Size-Choice</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You are of Medium size.</p> 
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are of Medium size.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM"/>			
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Small" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_SIZE_S">
		<supports>Human-Onepiece-Size-Choice</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You are of Small size.</p> 
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are of Small size.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_SMALL"/>			
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Human Determination" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_HUMAN_DETERMINATION">
		<description>
			<p>Once when you're reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can choose to fall to 1 hit point instead. You must finish a long rest before you can use this trait again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>Once when you're reduced to 0 hit points but not killed, you can choose to fall to 1 hit point instead..</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Human Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_SUBRACE">
		<description>
			<p>Choose between standard human, kuja, long-arm, long-leg, snakeneck or three-eye tribe.<br /></p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Human Subrace" supports="Human-Onepiece" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Standard Human" type="Sub Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_SUB_RACE_HUMAN_STANDARD">
		<supports>Human-Onepiece</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You are a common human, the most numerous among the world's inhabitants. While your origins are unremarkable, you nonetheless have a power within you to make your own future. </p>
			<p>     
				<span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Standard humans tend towards no particular alignment. The best and worst of all people are represented among their numbers.<br />
				<span class="feature">Resourcefulness.</span>You gain proficiency with one skill or one simple or martial weapon of your choice.<br />
				<span class="feature">Strong Will.</span>When you fail a saving throw, you can roll a d4 and add it to the roll, possibly changing the outcome. You can do this a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and regain all uses when you finish a long rest.<br />
			</p>  
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Resourcefulness (Human Onepiece)" supports="Human-Onepiece-Proficiency-Choice"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_STANDARD_STRONG_WILL" />						
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Size Options" supports="Human-Onepiece-Size-Choice" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Skill" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_STANDARD_RESOURCEFULLNESS_SKILL">
		<supports>Human-Onepiece-Proficiency-Choice</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with one skill.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency" supports="Skill" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Weapon" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_STANDARD_RESOURCEFULLNESS_WEAPON">
		<supports>Human-Onepiece-Proficiency-Choice</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with one one weapon of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Weapon Proficiency" supports="Weapon" /> 
		</rules>
	</element>

	
	<element name="Strong Will" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_STANDARD_STRONG_WILL">
		<description>
			<p>When you fail a saving throw, you can roll a d4 and add it to the roll, possibly changing the outcome. You can do this a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and regain all uses when you finish a long rest.<br /></p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage= "{{proficiency}}/Long Rest" >
			<description>When you fail a saving throw, you can roll a d4 and add it to the roll, possibly changing the outcome. You can do this a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and regain all uses when you finish a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>


	<element name="Kuja Tribe" type="Sub Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_SUB_RACE_HUMAN_KUJA_TRIBE">
		<supports>Human-Onepiece</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Kuja are an all-female amazonian subset of humans that live secluded on the island of Amazon Lily located in the Calm Belt. Most if not all Kuja are trained warriors, and even the common soldier can wield minor armament haki.  <br />
				
				<span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Kuja are typically only concerned with the wellbeing of their queen and society, favoring lawful alignments with a strong neutral bend. <br />
				<span class="feature">Amazon Training.</span>You have proficiency with longbows,shortbows, shortswords and spears.<br />
				<span class="feature">Minor Haki.</span>When you make a weapon attack that lets you add your proficiency bonus to the attack roll, you can choose to temporarily infuse the weapon with haki. You can add a d4 to the the damage roll of this weapon attack, and the weapon is considered haki-imbued for the purpose of overcoming resistances and immunities. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and regain all uses when you finish a long rest.<br />
			</p>  			
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>			
			<grant type="Proficiency" name ="Amazon Training" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_GROUP_BOWS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" name ="Amazon Training" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_GROUP_SPEARS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" name ="Amazon Training" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" />			
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Size Options" supports="Human-Onepiece-Size-Choice" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" name="Minor Haki" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_KUJA_TRIBE_MINOR_HAKI" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Minor Haki" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_KUJA_TRIBE_MINOR_HAKI">
		<description>
			<p>When you make a weapon attack that lets you add your proficiency bonus to the attack roll, you can choose to temporarily infuse the weapon with haki. You can add a d4 to the the damage roll of this weapon attack, and the weapon  is considered haki-imbued for the purpose of overcoming resistances and immunities. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your proficiency bonus, and regain all uses when you finish a long rest.<br /></p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage= "{{proficiency}}/Long Rest" >
			<description>When you make a weapon attack that lets you add your proficiency bonus to the attack roll, you can choose to temporarily infuse the weapon with haki. You can add a d4 to the the damage roll of this weapon attack, and the weapon is considered haki-imbued for the purpose of overcoming resistances and immunities.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>



	<element name="Long-Leg Tribe" type="Sub Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_SUB_RACE_HUMAN_LONG_LEG_TRIBE">
		<supports>Human-Onepiece</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Humans of the Long-leg tribe are defined by their abnormally long and powerful legs, which they are quite proud of and happily show off by eschewing legwear. They have a longstanding rivalry with the Long-arm tribe. <br />
				
				<span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Like Long-arm humans, Long-leg humans gravitate towards chaos. They have no strong disposition towards good or evil. <br />
				<span class="feature">Tall Stride.</span>Your walking speed increases by 5 feet, and the distance you can cover with a high or long jump doubles.<br />
				<span class="feature">Sprint.</span>When you move on your turn, you can double your speed until the end of the turn. Once you use this trait, you can’t use it again until you move 0 feet on one of your turns.<br />
			    <span class="feature">Size</span>You are of Medium size.
			</p> 
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
			<p>
				<br />
				You are of Medium size.	<br/>
				The distance you can cover with a high or long jump doubles.<br/>
				</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="5"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_LONG_LEG_TRIBE_SPRINT" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM"/>
		</rules>
	</element>


	<element name="Sprint" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_LONG_LEG_TRIBE_SPRINT">
		<description>
			<p>When you move on your turn, you can double your speed until the end of the turn. Once you use this trait, you can’t use it again until you move 0 feet on one of your turns.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage= "1/Turn with 0 feet of movement" >
			<description>On your turn, you can have {{sprint:distance}} feet of movement speed until the end of the turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="sprint:distance" value="innate speed" />
			<stat name="sprint:distance" value="innate speed" />
		</rules>
	</element>


	<element name="Long-Arm Tribe" type="Sub Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_SUB_RACE_HUMAN_LONG_ARM_TRIBE">
		<supports>Human-Onepiece</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Humans of the Long-arm tribe possess an additional elbow in their arms, extending their reach much greater than other tribes. This typically gives them a lanky appearence that distinguishes them from other humans. <br />
				
				<span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Long-arm humans have no particular tendency towards any alignment, however due to a longstanding conflict with long-leg tribes they are warlike in nature, gravitating towards chaos. <br />
				<span class="feature">Long Limbs.</span>When you make a weapon attack or unarmed strike on your turn, your reach with the weapon or your unarmed strikes increases by 5 feet.<br />
				<span class="feature">Sudden Reach.</span>You have advantage on opportunity attacks.<br />
			</p> 
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
			<p>
				<br />
				You have advantage on opportunity attacks.<br/>
				</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="5"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_BUGBEAR_LONG_LIMBED" />
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Size Options" supports="Human-Onepiece-Size-Choice" />			
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Three-Eye Tribe" type="Sub Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_SUB_RACE_HUMAN_THREE_EYE_TRIBE">
		<supports>Human-Onepiece</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Humans of the Three-eye tribe are few and far between, valued for the potential to hear the "voice of all things", which allow a person to read poneglyphs. Many conceal their third eye for fear of persecution or discrimination. <br />
				
				<span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Three-eye humans have no specific tendencies towards neither good nor evil. <br />
				<span class="feature">Keeper of Secrets.</span>You have advantage on Deception and Insight skills. <br />
				<span class="feature">Third Eye.</span>. You have advantage on saving throws against being blinded or charmed, and on all ability checks you make to see through illusions and mirages.<br />
				<span class="feature">Secret Potential.</span>When you gain an Ability Score Increase, you are eligible to choose the Voice of All Things haki feat in place of increasing an ability score.<br />
			</p> 
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
			<p>
				<br />
				You have advantage on Deception and Insight skills, saving throws against being blinded or charmed, and on all ability checks you make to see through illusions and mirages.<br/>
				</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>			
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Size Options" supports="Human-Onepiece-Size-Choice" />	
			<grant type="Racial Trait" name="Secret Potenial"  id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_THREE_EYE_TRIBE_SECRET_POTENTIAL" />
		</rules>
	</element>


	<element name="Secret Potenial" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_THREE_EYE_TRIBE_SECRET_POTENTIAL">
		<description>
			<p>When you gain an Ability Score Increase, you are eligible to choose the Voice of All Things haki feat in place of increasing an ability score.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you gain an Ability Score Increase, you are eligible to choose the Voice of All Things haki feat in place of increasing an ability score.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>



	<element name="Snakeneck Tribe" type="Sub Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_SUB_RACE_HUMAN_SNAKENECK_TRIBE">
		<supports>Human-Onepiece</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Humans of the Snakeneck tribe are defined by their elongated necks, and often have slender bodies to match. Pragmatic in nature, they tend to favor cold logic over emotionally driven decisions. <br />
				
				<span class="feature">Alignment.</span>. Snakeneck humans typically are as varied as other humans, however some possess an innate sadistic streak that prompts them towards evil. <br />
				<span class="feature">Steady Mind.</span>You can add your proficiency bonus to any initiative roll you make. Once when you are surprised while you are conscious, you can choose to act normally on your turn, and must finish a long rest before you can do so again. <br />
				<span class="feature">Towering Gaze.</span>. You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks relying on sight.<br/>
			</p> 
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
			<p>
				<br />
				You can add your proficiency bonus to any initiative roll you make.<br/>
				</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>			
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Size Options" supports="Human-Onepiece-Size-Choice" />	
			<grant type="Racial Trait" name="Steady Mind"  id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_SNAKENECK_TRIBE_STEADY_MIND" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" name="Towering Gaze"  id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_SNAKENECK_TRIBE_TOWERING_GAZE" />
			<stat name="initiative" value="proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Steady Mind" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_SNAKENECK_TRIBE_STEADY_MIND">
		<description>
			<p>Once when you are surprised while you are conscious, you can choose to act normally on your turn, and must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage= "1/Long Rest" >
			<description>Once when you are surprised while you are conscious, you can choose to act normally on your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Towering Gaze" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_HUMAN_SNAKENECK_TRIBE_TOWERING_GAZE">
		<description>
			<p>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks relying on sight.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks relying on sight.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
</elements>
	
	
	
	
