<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Human-Onepiece</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/HkRwCRCxU">u/Mr-Silvers and Eiichiro Oda</author>
		<update version="3.1.1">
			<file name="race-merfolk.xml" url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/HkRwCRCxU"/>
		</update>
	</info>

    <element name="Merfolk" type="Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACE_MERFOLK">
        <description>
            <p class="flavour">Merfolk are humanoid creatures with the upper body of a human and the lower body of a marine creature, typically a fish or an octopus. Unlike fishmen, the human side of merfolk does not necessarily bear any piscine features, though it is not unheard of for some merfolk to have more marine traits such as fins or webbed fingers.<br/> Related to the fishmen, merfolk make their home beneath the Red Line on fishman island. The two races exist in harmony, sharing a similar difficult history with the surface world and the races that inhabit it. But whereas fishmen are feared and infamous for being savages, merfolk have a much more favorable reputation among humans as beings of extreme beauty. Sadly, this reputation only serves to make them more desirable as slaves on the underworld markets, leading to many cases of abductions at the hands of pirates. <br/> Despite these unfortunate circumstances, merfolk have remained firmly open-minded towards all other races, including humans. Kind-hearted and gregarious to a fault, merfolk have a reputation for saving drowning sailors from the depths only to disappear moments afterwards.</p>
           
            <h4>DEEP SEA MONARCHS</h4>
            <p>While not as physically imposing or martially bent as fishmen, merfolk have a keen eye for politics and diplomacy, being the current rulers of Fishman Island under King Neptune. While the common fishman has the advantage in a one on one fight, the merfolk's ability to organize and manage a standing army makes them the obvious figureheads in politics with the surface world.<br/> Merfolk are very hospitable and welcoming to travelers that reach Fishman Island, which is a common occurance as it's the only way to travel from Paradise to the New World. As long as visitors come in peace and with no ill intent, the merfolk will graciously host any traveler during their stay whether they are pirates or marine soldiers.<br/> While peaceful, merfolk are not naive however. If provoked, merfolk will respond in kind if their hands are forced, many of their soldiers and warriors having mastered a unique form of Fishman Karate unique to their kind. Being the fastest swimmers of all intelligent races, coupled with their organized military, make merfolk a force to be reckoned with even when battle is at hand. </p>
           
            <h4>GREGARIOUS HELPERS</h4>
            <p>Merfolk delight in song, music and all forms of community based entertainment. Their's is a tight-knit community that lacks social stigma or class differences, each individual treated as a cherished part of the community as long as they are honest and kind-hearted in turn. Merfolk and fishmen typically consider themselves kin of eachother and rarely make a difference between the two.<br/> Interbreeding between the two races has an equal chance of producing either a merfolk or fishman child, and most carry genes from both species with them resulting in a sense of unity and equality between the two races.<br/> Merfolk may still have some reservations about humans, but these prejudices typically stem from fear or ignorance, which can usually be remedied through nothing but a few minutes of pleasant conversation. Most merfolk would much rather make a new friend rather than an enemy, and typically treat strangers as potential friends or allies with more openmindedness than most other species.<br/> Merfolk's friendly and approachable nature isn't limited only to other sapient beings. All mermaids can communicate and speak with fish, having a much easier time doing so than even fishmen. They can use this ability to call fish to their aid, which can be used for scouting or to gather information on the surrounding waters.</p>
            
            <h4>Merfolk Traits</h4>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> One ability score of your choice increases by 2, and another one increases by 1. Alternatively,three ability scores of your choice increase by 1.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Age.</span>Humans reach adulthood in their late teens and live less than a century.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Alignment.</span> Merfolk are naturally amiable and kindhearted, gravitating towards good alignments. They have a strong focus on community and coexistence, making them tend towards law over chaos.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Size.</span> Merfolk are usually the same size as humans, though exceptions that vary to the extremes do exist. The ones presented here are human-sized. Your size is medium. <br/>
                <span class="feature">Speed.</span> Your base walking speed is 10 feet. Your base swimming speed is 40 ft. <br/>
                <span class="feature">Darkvision.</span>Accustomed to the dark ocean floors where light is scarce, you have darkvision out to 60 feet and can see in dim light as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Aquatic Adaption.</span> You can breathe air and water. You have advantage on all Strength (Athletic) ability checks made while in water <br/>
                <span class="feature">Bubble Floater.</span> When near a body of water, you can create a bubble floater around your midsection as an action. While you have this floater, your walking speed increases by 20. The floater lasts for 8 hours. <br/>
                <span class="feature">Call for Aid.</span> As an action, you can summon a swarm of fish in an empty square within 10 feet of you that is a body of water (pg.9). The swarm is friendly to you and your allies, and obeys your command for 1 hour. Roll initiative for the swarm separately when in combat. It obeys any verbal commands that you issue to it (no action required by you). If you don’t issue any commands to it, it defends itself from hostile creatures, but otherwise takes no actions. Once you use this trait, you cannot use it again until you finish a long rest <br/>
                <span class="feature">Friend of the Sea.</span> You can speak with creatures with a natural swimming speed that are of huge size or smaller. Though simple-minded, sea creatures can understand the words you speak. Additionally, you have advantage on Wisdom (Animal Handling) ability checks made towards marine creatures.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Pure Soul.</span> You have advantage on Intelligence, Wisdom and Charisma saving throws.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Languages.</span> You can speak, read, and write Common and one extra language of your choice. Merfolk typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with, including obscure dialects.
            </p>
			<div class="reference">
				<div element="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH" />
			</div>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <setters>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}} {{surname}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="3d6">7'9"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d4">110 lb.</set>
		</setters>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Improvement Type" source="Internal" supports="Custom Ability Score Improvement Option"/>
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM"/>
            <stat  name= "innate speed" value="10" bonus="base"/>
            <stat  name= "innate speed:swim" value="40" bonus="base" />	
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />		
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<select type="Language" name="Customized Language" supports="Custom Race Language"  />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_AQUATIC_ADAPTATION" />

        </rules>
    </element>

<!--  use reference mod of a companion (hypotetical)  for fish sworm  -->

	<element name="Swarm of Fish" type="Companion" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH">
		<setters>
			<set name="strength">8</set>
			<set name="dexterity">15</set>
			<set name="constitution">9</set>
			<set name="intelligence">1</set>
			<set name="wisdom">14</set>
			<set name="charisma">2</set>
			<set name="ac">12</set>
			<set name="hp">5 (1d6+1)</set>
			<set name="speed">0 ft., swim 40 ft.</set>
			<set name="senses">darkvision 60 ft., passive Perception 12+pb</set>
			<set name="skills">Deception +4, Insight +3, Persuasion +4, Stealth +5</set>
			<set name="resistances">bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing </set>
            <set name="condition immunities">charmed, frightened, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, prone, restrained and stunned </set>            
			<set name="type">Beast</set>
			<set name="size">Medium swarm of tiny</set>
			<set name="alignment">unaligned</set>
			<set name="challenge">1</set>
			<set name="traits">ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH_TRAIT_SEARCH_PARTY,ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH_TRAIT_SWARM,ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH_TRAIT_WATER_BREATHING</set>
			<set name="actions">ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH_ACTION_NIBBELS_1,ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH_ACTION_NIBBELS_2</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="companion:ac" value="12" />
			<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="5" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level" bonus="base"/>
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level" bonus="base"/>
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level" bonus="base"/>
            <stat name="companion:hp:max" value="level" bonus="base"/>
            <stat name="darkvision:range" value="60" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:speed" value="0" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:speed:swim" value="40" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:perception:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="companion:survival:proficiency" value="companion:proficiency" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Search Party" type="Companion Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH_TRAIT_SEARCH_PARTY">
		<description>
			<p>The swarm has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Wisdom (Survival) checks while it has more than half its maximum hit points.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The swarm has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) and Wisdom (Survival) checks while it has more than half its maximum hit points.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Swarm" type="Companion Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH_TRAIT_SWARM">
		<description>
			<p>The swarm can occupy another creature's space and vice versa, and the swarm can move through any opening large enough for a tiny fish. The swarm can't regain hit points or gain temporary hit points.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The swarm can occupy another creature's space and vice versa, and the swarm can move through any opening large enough for a tiny fish. The swarm can't regain hit points or gain temporary hit points.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Water Breathing" type="Companion Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH_TRAIT_WATER_BREATHING">
		<description>
			<p>The swarm can breathe only underwater.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The swarm can breathe only underwater.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Nibbles (Swarm has more than half HP)" type="Companion Action" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH_ACTION_NIBBELS_1">
		<description>
			<p>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 +{{proficiency}} to hit, reach 0 ft., one creature in the swarm's space. Hit: 5 (2d4) piercing damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 +{{proficiency}} to hit, reach 0 ft., one creature in the swarm's space. Hit: 5 (2d4) piercing damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Nibbles (Swarm has less than half HP)" type="Companion Action" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_SWARM_OF_FISH_ACTION_NIBBELS_2">
		<description>
			<p>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 +{{proficiency}} to hit, reach 0 ft., one creature in the swarm's space. Hit: 2 (1d4) piercing damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 +{{proficiency}} to hit, reach 0 ft., one creature in the swarm's space. Hit: 2 (1d4) piercing damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>



    <element name="Friend of the Sea" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_FRIEND_OF_THE_SEA">
        <description>
            <p>You can speak with creatures with a natural swimming speed that are of huge size or smaller. Though simple-minded, sea creatures can understand the words you speak. Additionally, you have advantage on Wisdom (Animal Handling) ability checks made towards marine creatures.<br/></p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can speak with creatures with a natural swimming speed that are of huge size or smaller. You have advantage on Wisdom (Animal Handling) ability checks made towards marine creatures</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Bubble Floater" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_BUBBLE_FLOATER">
        <description>
            <p>When near a body of water, you can create a bubble floater around your midsection as an action. While you have this floater, your walking speed increases by 20. The floater lasts for 8 hours.<br/></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage= "Lasts 8 hours">
            <description>When near a body of water, you can create a bubble floater around your midsection as an action. While you have this floater, your walking speed increases by 20</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>


	<element name="Bubble Floater" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_MERFOLK_BUBBLE_FLOATER">
        <description>
            <p>When near a body of water, you can create a bubble floater around your midsection as an action. While you have this floater, your walking speed increases by 20. The floater lasts for 8 hours.<br/></p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage= "Lasts 8 hours">
            <description>When near a body of water, you can create a bubble floater around your midsection as an action. While you have this floater, your walking speed increases by 20</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>




</elements>