<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Fishman</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/ItlMSW6ztZTm">oneworldhd and Eiichiro Oda</author>
		<update version="3.11.1">
			<file name="race-fishman.xml" url="https://homebrewery.naturalcrit.com/share/ItlMSW6ztZTm"/>
		</update>
	</info>

    <element name="Fishman" type="Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACE_FISHMAN">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">Fishmen, along with Merfolk, are one of the two races of humanoids that inhabit the sea. Fishmen are a roughly equal mix of Human and Fish, with human-like appendages and faces crossed with sea creatures such as sharks, blowfish, and other fish. They also have gills between their shoulders and necks, as well as often having webbed hands. Some species of fish-men may have extra appendages depending what on what species of fish they represent.<br/> Fishmen have both lungs and gills, which allow them to breathe underwater and on land. Their webbed fingers and agile bodies allow them to move quickly in water for as long as they want. Some fishmen use their naturally strong bodies and unique features as a reason to believe they are superior to Humans. Despite these beliefs, fish-men often end up being the ones to become enslaved and oppressed by Humans, which drives their hatred for them even further. However, not all fish-men think this way and can actually get along well with humans as equals.<br/></p>
		
			<h4>HYBRIDS</h4>
			<p>Fishmen have the ability to interbreed with other races, much like other humanoid races. It is not impossible to find half-humna or half-giant fishmen in places such as the grand line. Furthermore, fishmen can have children with merfolk, resulting in either a fishman or merfolk child being born.<br/> </p>
		
			<h4>OPPRESSED</h4>
			<p>Like other non-human races, fish-men are the victims of world-wide oppression by humans. Due to this, many fish-men stay within the confines of fish-man island and only occasionally leave. Some evil fish-men have opted to be pirates to seek revenge against humanity. Unfortunately, several also end up as slaves under the world government. Even on islands not directly under world government jurisdiction, humans still treat fish-men very unfairly. For this reason, playing a fish-man can prove very different when visiting various human-inhabited islands around the sea.<br/> </p>
				
			<h4>DOMINATION</h4>
			<p>Though they are often misunderstood, many fish-men do hold the belief that they should rule over all other fish in the sea. And due to the cruel treatment they receive from humans, some grow to also want to conquer and rule over humanity as a whole. This isn't true of all fish-men though, as many do exhibit the desire to co-exist with other races and species.<br/> </p>

			<h4>EXTRAORDINARY STRENGTH</h4>
			<p>As well as being born with bodies that provide natural weapons in battles, such as razor-sharp teeth, fish-men have incredibly strong bodies compared to average people. From birth, fish-men are ten times stronger than humans. Additionally, fish-men can be even more troublesome in underwater combat. Being even stronger underwater, they can easily devastate a human who isn't proficient at swimming. Unfortunately, this strength can be negated if a fish-man happens to be a Devil Fruit user.<br/> </p>

			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your consitution score increases by 1.<br />
				<span class="feature">Age.</span>Fishmen reach adulthood in their late teens and live around a century.<br />
                <span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Most fish-men are lawful and many stay true to their values, though some lean toward being neutral. Fish-men can live in harmony with other sea creatures, but may turn violent against humans. For this reason, a fish-man can range from being good to evil.<br />
				<span class="feature">Size.</span>Fish-men are between 7 and 8 feet tall and weigh between 280 and 340 pounds on average. Your size is medium.<br />
				<span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet, and you have a Swimming speed of 35 feet. <br />
				<span class="feature">Languages.</span>You can speak, read, and write Common and one extra language of your choice. Fishmen typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with, including obscure dialects.<br />
				<span class="feature">Amphibious.</span>You can breathe air and water.<br />
				<span class="feature">Underwater Athlete.</span>You have proficiency in the Strength (Athletics). While underwater, you face no penalties or disadvantage as a result of underwater combat rules.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Adapted to the Sea.</span>With the ability to adapt to extreme underwater depths, you have Resistance to cold damage.<br/>
                <span class="feature">Subrace.</span>Choose between: Shark, Manta Ray, Octopus, or Smelt-Whiting. <br />
			</p>        
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<setters>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}} {{surname}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="3d6">7'9"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d4">300 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM"/>
			<stat name="constitution" value="1" alt="Fishman"/>
			<stat  name= "innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
            <stat name="innate speed:swim" value="35" />	
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" name="Underwater Athlete" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_UNDRWATER_ATHLETE" /> 
			<grant type="Racial Trait" name="Adapted to the Sea" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_ADAPTED_TO_THE_SEA" /> 
            <grant type="Racial Trait" name="Fishman Subrace" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_SUBRACE" /> 
		</rules>
	</element>


    <element name="Underwater Athlete" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_UNDRWATER_ATHLETE">
        <description>
            <p>While underwater, you face no penalties or disadvantage as a result of underwater combat rules.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While underwater, you face no penalties or disadvantage as a result of underwater combat rules.</description>
        </sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
		</rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Adapted to the Sea" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_ADAPTED_TO_THE_SEA">
        <description>
            <p>With the ability to adapt to extreme underwater depths, you have Resistance to cold damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have Resistance to cold damage.</description>
        </sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
		</rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Fishman Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_SUBRACE">
		<description>
			<p>Breeding among fish-people resulted in four main subraces: Shark, Manta Ray, Octopus, or Smelt-Whiting variants.<br /></p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Fishman Subrace" supports="Fishman" />
		</rules>
	</element>


    <element name="Shark" type="Sub Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_SUB_RACE_FISHMAN_SHARK">
		<supports>Fishman</supports>
		<description>
			<p>These fish-men are known to have sharp shark-like teeth, light blue-tinted skin, large back fins, and extreme strength. </p>
			<p>     
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Strength score increases by 2.<br />
				<span class="feature">Apex Predtaor.</span>You gain proficiency in the Charisma (Intimidation).<br />
				<span class="feature">Bite.</span>Your razor-sharp teeth are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an Unarmed Strike.<br />
			</p>  
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="2" alt="Shark Fishman"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_SHARK_BITE" />
		</rules>
	</element>


    <element name="Bite" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_SHARK_BITE">
		<description>
			<p>Your razor-sharp teeth are a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an Unarmed Strike.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> When you use your unarmed strikes, you deal 1d6 + {{strength:modifier}} piercing damage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

    <element name="Manta Ray" type="Sub Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_SUB_RACE_FISHMAN_MANTA_RAY">
		<supports>Fishman</supports>
		<description>
			<p>These fish-men are known to have wide side-fins and light-blue skin, moving at high speeds underwater. </p>
			<p>  
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Dexterity score increases by 2.<br />   
				<span class="feature">Underwater Acrobatics.</span>You gain proficiency in Dexteriry (Acrobatics). You have advantage on acrobatics check made while underwater.<br />
				<span class="feature">Sea Glide.</span>You have a Swimming speed of 40 feet.<br />
			</p>  
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dexterity" value="2" alt="Manta Ray Fishman"/>
			<stat name="innate speed:swim" value="5" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_MANTA_RAY_UNDERWATER_ACROBATICS" />
		</rules>
	</element>

    <element name="Underwater Acrobatics" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_MANTA_RAY_UNDERWATER_ACROBATICS">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency in Dexteriry (Acrobatics). You have advantage on acrobatics check made while underwater.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on acrobatics check made while underwater.</description>
		</sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS" />           
        </rules>
	</element>

    <element name="Octopus" type="Sub Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_SUB_RACE_FISHMAN_OCTOPUS">
		<supports>Fishman</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Octopus fish-men tend to have six arms and red or brown-tinted skin, with a lot of flexibility with their multiple appendages. </p>
			<p>     
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Strength and Dexterity scores both increase by 1.<br />   
				<span class="feature">Deadly Precision.</span>You gain proficiency in one of the following: Dexteriry (Sleight of hand) or an Artisan's tool of your choice.<br />
				<span class="feature">Multi-armed</span>You have four additional arms, six in total. While you cannot efficiently wield weapons with these arms, you may use them to hold smaller items such as potions and trinkets. Additionally, you have advantage on grapple checks with your arms.<br />
			</p>  
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You have up to four additional arms.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1" alt="Octopus Fishman"/>
			<stat name="dexterity" value="1" alt="Octopus Fishman"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_OCTOPUS_DEADLY_PRECISION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_OCTOPUS_MULTIARMED" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Deadly Precision" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_OCTOPUS_DEADLY_PRECISION">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency in one of the following: Dexteriry (Sleight of hand) or an Artisan's tool of your choice.</p>
		</description>
        <rules>
            <select type="Racial Trait" name="Deadly Precision Feature" supports="Octopus"/>         
        </rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Sleight of Hand" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_OCTOPUS_DEADLY_PRECISION_SOH">
		<supports>Octopus</supports>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />       
        </rules>
	</element>    

	<element name="Artisan's Tool Proficiency" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_OCTOPUS_DEADLY_PRECISION_ATP">
		<supports>Octopus</supports>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ARTISANS_TOOLS" />         
        </rules>
	</element> 

	<element name="Multi-armed" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_OCTOPUS_MULTIARMED">
		<description>
			<p>You have four additional arms, six in total. While you cannot efficiently wield weapons with these arms, you may use them to hold smaller items such as potions and trinkets. Additionally, you have advantage on grapple checks with your arms.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have four additional arms, six in total. While you cannot efficiently wield weapons with these arms, you may use them to hold smaller items such as potions and trinkets. Additionally, you have advantage on grapple checks with your arms.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>


	<element name="Smelt-Whiting" type="Sub Race" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_SUB_RACE_SMELT_WHITING">
		<supports>Fishman</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Smelt-whiting fish-men are known to have more dominant fish-like characteristics compared to other fish-men, and can spit water at their enemies. </p>
			<p>     
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Charisma score increases by 2.<br />   
				<span class="feature">Big-Mouthed.</span>You gain proficiency in either Charisma (Deception) or Charisma (Persuasion). <br />
				<span class="feature">Multi-armed</span>You have four additional arms, six in total. While you cannot efficiently wield weapons with these arms, you may use them to hold smaller items such as potions and trinkets. Additionally, you have advantage on grapple checks with your arms.<br />
			</p>  
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description> You have up to four additional arms.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="2" alt="Smelt-Whiting Fishman"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_SMELT_WHITING_BIG_MOUTHED" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_SMELT_WHITING_HYDRO_CANNON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
    
	<element name="Big-Mouthed" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_SMELT_WHITING_BIG_MOUTHED">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency in either Charisma (Deception) or Charisma (Persuasion).</p>
		</description>
        <rules>
            <select type="Racial Trait" name="Big-Mouthed Feature" supports="Smelt-Whiting"/>         
        </rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Deception" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_SMELT_WHITING_BIG_MOUTHED_DEC">
		<supports>Smelt-Whiting</supports>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />       
        </rules>
	</element>    

	<element name="Artisan's Tool Persuasion" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_SMELT_WHITING_BIG_MOUTHED_PER">
		<supports>Smelt-Whiting</supports>
        <rules>
             <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION" />      
        </rules>
	</element> 

    <element name="Hydro Cannon" type="Racial Trait" source="One Piece Homebrew" id="ID_OP_RACIAL_TRAIT_FISHMAN_SMELT_WHITING_HYDRO_CANNON">
		<description>
			<p>You have the natural ability to shoot concentrated blasts of water out of your mouth. You can cast ray of frost with this trait. Starting at 3rd Level, you can cast Ice Knife with it. Once you Cast a Spell with this trait, you can't cast that spell with it again until you finish a Long Rest. Charisma is your Spellcasting Ability for these Spells.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have the natural ability to shoot concentrated blasts of water out of your mouth.</description>
			<description>You can cast ray of frost with this trait. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</description>
			<description level="3">You can cast ray of frost with this trait. You can cast Ice Knife spell once per long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RRAY_OF_FROST" level="1" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_KNIFE" level="3" />
		</rules>
	</element>




</elements>